Now that we know how to create lists, let's start doing some more complicated and more exciting things.
So now that we have this list called friends, maybe we no longer want to invite.
Let's say we don't want to invite Sarah to the party anymore.
And we want to change this value.
We want to make it dynamic, because at the moment it's a static list that's been set in the program.
So dynamic means that we can change the values inside this list called friends.
But let's ask them, what command do you think you're going to use to allow the user to change the value
that is stored inside of this list?
Sorry, what did you say?
I can't hear you.
You're going to have to shut up.
Understand?
We are miles away from you.
What did you say?
Did you say.
Oh, I think I heard input.
Well done.
That's exactly.
That's it.
Definitely been listening.
Okay, so first, before we ask the user to input the name, we're going to have to tell our list friends
what value we want to change.
So it's pretty similar to what we did before using indexing.
So say we like we said we wanted to change this value Sarah which was index.
Hopefully you remember two.
Uh, okay.
Index 2012.
We want to change no longer to Sara, but to.
Let's say my dad replaced me.
And we want to check that the list has actually changed.
So we want to then print that list and maybe to actually double check that it definitely changed.
We want to first print what the list was before we change the value, and then print what the list was
after we changed the value.
So the first line that prints is going to be the list before the second line, the list after.
Okay.
So you can see the first one was what we typed here.
Then we decided no, we don't want Sara anymore.
Let's change that value to Craig.
And it's just changed that value zero to being Craig.
But perhaps we want to make it more exciting.
And like we were saying earlier, we want the user to input who they want coming.
So okay, so instead of us deciding we want that equal to friend, we're going to ask again the user
and lack you so cleverly remembered earlier.
We use input.
So we're just going to now type in a prompt.
So this is the part that comes in inverted commas asking the user the question type a friend's name.
And so where's this friend's name going to be stored.
It's going to be stored in the list in position two.
So we can see the list what it looks like at the moment Mary Fred Sarah Charlie.
And we're going to try Claire.
And there we go now Mary, Fred Claire and Charlie.
So the user is now actually inputting a value, but it's being stored in a position inside the list.
And remember if this we changed to four and we asked them to type in let's just go the same.
What do you think is going to happen.
It's going to get an error because there is no position four in that list.
We've got zero, one, two, three.
Charlie is the last one in that position.
Three can only change what is already in the list.
So those are lists.
You're getting a fair idea.
And again it's a very important tool very important variable type in the sense that you can use and
manipulate.
And they become very powerful when we look later on at loops, because you can now run around a loop
and list and fill it very quickly or print it out.
So they are really handy.
You can have lots of fun, so have some fun.
Play with your lists.
They are an important part of organizing life.